

LÊ BÌNH PHƯƠNG

SYSDEVOPS LEAD

+84-559 522 667

info@binhphuong.io.vn | binhphuong.pcsr@gmail.com



binhphuong.io.vn

ABOUT ME

With over 9 years of comprehensive experience in Information Technology, I've embraced a diverse spectrum of roles, encompassing IT Infrastructure, System Administration and a focus on DevOps. Presently, I occupy the senior-most position as a SysDevOps Lead.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2017 - Present

7-Eleven | Ho Chi Minh City

SysDevOps Lead

- Managed and optimized costs for cloud infrastructure, ensuring efficient resource allocation and cost-effective solutions.
- Designed, deployed, and managed microservice systems on the Kubernetes platform, enhancing scalability, resilience, as well as the high performance and reliability of server and network systems.
- Managed over 150+ servers, 50+ services and 20+ databases with 99.9% up-time.
- Conducted research on new solutions to enhance performance and security, implementing innovative measures to mitigate risks and improve efficiency.
- Developed automation systems to optimize application deployment processes, streamlining workflows and reducing manual intervention.
- Established monitoring, alerting, and security systems, ensuring proactive detection and response to potential threats and vulnerabilities.
- Implemented robust disaster recovery systems, ensuring business continuity and minimizing downtime in case of emergencies.
- Provided direction and guided the development roadmap for DevOps team, fostering skill development and aligning team goals with organizational objectives.

IT Infrastructure TeamLead

- Developed and managed systems including Active Directory (AD), DNS, File server, Backup, Email, Monitoring, VPN, Camera
- Deployed and managed network systems for Datacenter, Office and Stores.
- Identified opportunities for process optimization and automation, implementing solutions to improve efficiency and productivity.
- Automated setup processes for computers and point-of-sale (POS) systems.
- Deployed and managed asset management systems
- Developed internal systems with Google Cloud Platform.
- Liaised with vendors for procurement, maintenance, and support of IT infrastructure components.
- Provided training and guidance to team members on new technologies, processes, and best practices, fostering skill development and enhancing team capabilities.
- Coordinated with various departments to expedite store setup and operations, ensuring efficient workflow and timely completion.

2018 - 2019

ODS JSC | Ho Chi Minh City

VolP Engineer

- Built, managed and Integrated PBX core systems with various network providers such as FPT, Viettel, Mobifone, Vinaphone, and others, ensuring system compatibility and reliability.
- Ensured stable operation and high performance of VoIP systems for over 500 clients, including system management and monitoring.
- · Worked closely with other teams such as software development, technical support, and business departments to ensure effectiveness and meet customer needs.

0 2015 - 2018

Vingroup | Ho Chi Minh City

IT Coordinator

staff for IT-related issues.

- Setup of new stores, ensuring all IT infrastructure and systems are installed and operational.
- Managing network setup and configuration for new store locations, including routers, switches, and access points.
- Administering and maintaining Active Directory (AD) and DNS services.
- Providing technical support and troubleshooting assistance to store

TECH STACK

Kubernetes

Docker

Kafka

EFK vs PLG

GIT

Jira

Nginx

AWS/GCP

≥ SOFT SKILLS

Leadership

Planning and Strategy

Analytical and Problem Solving

Communication

SKILLS

Languages

Python, Go, Javascript, Shell, PowerShell, DiaPlan.

Infrastructure as Code

Terraform, Ansible, CloudFormation, Vagrant.

■ GitOps

Jenkins, ArgoCD, GitHub actions, AWS CodePipelines.

Cloud Infrastructure

Amazon AWS, Google GCP, OpenStack, VNG Cloud, FPT Cloud, OpenStack, VMWare.

Networking

Routers, Firewalls, Packet analysis, Socket, IPv4/v6, DNS, VPN, Cisco.

Security

WAF, Security Groups, NACL, Iptable, UFW, IDS, IPS, DDoS.

Monitoring and logging

Prometheus, Elasticsearch/Logstash/Kibana, Promtail/Loki/Grafana, Nagios, Newrelic.

Containers

Docker, Kubernetes.

Databases

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Mongo, SAP, Clickhouse, Replication, Backups and Recovery, Optimization & Normalization.

Operating Systems

Linux/Unix, Windows, MacOS.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Information Technology

Ho Chi Minh City University of Food Industry 2011 - 2015



LANGUAGES

English